She's primped. She's engaged. She's back.
Mulan II is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Lynne Southerland.
Fa Mulan gets the surprise of her young life when her love,
Captain Li Shang asks for her hand in marriage.
Before the two can have their happily ever after, the Emperor assigns them a
secret mission, to escort three princesses to Chang'an, China.
Mushu is determined to drive a wedge between the couple after he learns that he
will lose his guardian job if Mulan marries into the Li family.
Mulan (voice), played by Ming-Na Wen.
Shang (voice), played by BD Wong.
Mushu (voice), played by Mark Moseley.
Mei (voice), played by Lucy Liu.
Yao (voice), played by Harvey Fierstein.
Ting Ting (voice), played by Sandra Oh.
Mulan II is a 2004 American animated direct-to-video musical road adventure film produced by Disneytoon
Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Home Entertainment under the Walt Disney Pictures banner.
The film was directed by Darrell Rooney and Lynne Southerland (in her directorial debut) and produced by
Jennifer Blohm, from a screenplay written by Michael Lucker, Chris Parker, and Roger S.
Schulman, which was based on a story by Jenny Wingfield.
It is the sequel to Walt Disney Feature Animation's 1998 animated feature film Mulan, featuring original songs that were written
by composer Jeanine Tesori and lyricist Alexa Junge and a musical score composed and conducted by Joel McNeely.
Much of the voice cast from the first film returned, excluding Eddie Murphy (Mushu), Miriam Margolyes (The
Matchmaker), James Hong (Chi-Fu), Chris Sanders (Little Brother), and Matthew Wilder (Ling's singing voice).
Murphy, Margolyes, and Sanders were replaced by Mark Moseley, April Winchell, and Frank
Welker, respectively, while Gedde Watanabe does his own singing for the sequel.
Mulan II features Mulan and her new fiancé, General Li Shang, on a special mission: escorting the
Emperor's three daughters across the country to meet their soon-to-be fiancés.
Meanwhile, Mushu attempts to break up their relationship to keep his pedestal.
The film deals with arranged marriages, loyalty, relationships,
making choices, trust, and finding true love.
The film was released as a direct-to-video title in the United States on
December 28, 2004 and received negative reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of escape, arranged marriage, cartoon, musical, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted.